<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neng wang</title>
    <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on neng wang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.nengwang-economics.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/accepted/</guid>
      <description>Published and Accepted PapersLink to heading36 &amp;ldquo;An International Society for the Advancement of Economic Theory in its Relation to Statistics and Mathematics&amp;rdquo;, with HarrisonHong and Jinqiang Yang, Econometrica, accepted
35 &amp;ldquo;Mitigating Disaster Risks in the Age of Climate Change&amp;rdquo;, with Harrison Hong and Jinqiang Yang, Econometrica, accepted
34 &amp;ldquo;Welfare Consequences of Sustainable Finance,&amp;rdquo; with Harrison Hong, Neng Wang, and Jinqiang Yang, Review of Financial Studies, accepted
33 &amp;ldquo;The Endowment Model and Modern Portfolio Theory,&amp;rdquo; Stephen G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/other/</guid>
      <description>Other PublicationsLink to headingDynamic corporate finance under costly equity issuance, NBER Reporter 2, 10-13, 2021 Mitigating COVID-19 Risks to Sustain Growth, with Harrison Hong and Jinqiang Yang, in Impact of COVID-19 on Asian Economies and Policy Responses, eds. Sumit Agarwal, Zhiguo He and Bernard Yeung, 2021. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/working/</guid>
      <description>Working PapersLink to headingReputation, Competition, and Capital Structure, with Min Dai and Zhaoli Jiang &amp;ldquo;Strategic Investment under Uncertainty with First- and Second-mover Advantages&amp;rdquo;, with Min Dai and Zhaoli Jiang &amp;ldquo;Leverage Dynamics under Costly Equity Issuance&amp;rdquo;, with Patrick Bolton and Jinqiang Yang &amp;ldquo;Stochastic Earnings Growth and Equilibrium Wealth Distribution&amp;rdquo;, with Thomas J. Sargent and Jinqiang Yang &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Banking and the Value of Deposits&amp;rdquo;, with Patrick Bolton, Ye Li, and Jinqiang Yang Dynamic Trading with Realization Utility, with Min Dai and Cong Qin &amp;ldquo;A p Theory of Government Debt and Taxes&amp;rdquo;, with Wei Jiang, Thomas J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Published and Accepted PapersLink to heading39 &amp;ldquo;A p Theory of Taxes and Debt Management&amp;rdquo;, with Wei Jiang, Thomas J. Sargent, and Jinqiang Yang, Journal of Finance, forthcoming
38 &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Banking and the Value of Deposits&amp;rdquo;, with Patrick Bolton, Ye Li, and Jinqiang Yang, Journal of Finance, forthcoming
37 &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Trading with Realization Utility&amp;rdquo;, with Min Dai and Cong Qin, Journal of Finance, forthcoming
36 &amp;ldquo;A q Theory of Internal Capital Markets,&amp;rdquo; Min Dai, Xavier Giroud, Wei Jiang, and Neng Wang, Journal of Finance, 79(2), 1147-1197, (2024), https://doi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Current Academic AppointmentsLink to headingDean’s Distinguished Chair Professor of Finance and Senior Associate Dean, Cheung Kong Graduate School of Business (CKGSB), 2024 – present
Senior Fellow (Research Associate), National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), 2009 – present
Senior Fellow, Asian Bureau of Finance and Economic Research (ABFER), 2019 –
Past Academic AppointmentsLink to headingChong Khoon Lin Professor of Real Estate and Professor of Finance, Columbia Business School, Columbia University, July 2007 – Dec 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>中文信息</title>
      <link>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/zh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nengwang-economics.com/zh/</guid>
      <description>王能教授是长江商学院金融学教授、杰出院长讲席教授，学术高级副院长，美国哥伦比亚大学商学院金融学终身讲席教授，国民经济研究院(NBER)高级研究员，亚洲金融经济研究局(ABFER) 高级研究员。
王能教授1973年出生于安徽省马鞍山市当涂县，1992年毕业于南京大学少年班物理化学专业, 1995年获得加州理工学院化学硕士学位，1997年获得加州大学圣地亚哥分校国际关系及亚太研究硕士学位，2002年获得美国斯坦福大学商学院金融学博士学位。2002-2004年任教于美国罗切斯特大学商学院。自2004年任教于哥伦比亚大学，于2007年被破格提升为终身，讲席，正教授，时为哥伦比亚大学商学院最年轻的终身讲席正教授。2008-2011年曾任哥伦比亚大学商学院金融系主任。
王能教授的研究领域广泛，包括公司金融学，资产定价理论，宏观经济学，货币银行学，金融科技，消费金融学，创业金融学，金融机构，国际金融学，等。
王能教授以理论紧密结合实践的方式讲授MBA，EMBA，金融硕士及博士生课程，其中包括高级公司金融理论，高级资产定价理论，宏观经济学理论，创业金融学及私募股权，房地产金融，固定收益证券及市场，金融机构和风险管理等。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
